Guide to the G. Evelyn Hutchinson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1904-1991; Series I
  - DeLury, D. B. (Box 3, Folder 42)
    See also: Series I, folder 41
  - deRachewitz, Mary, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 197)
  - De Terra, Helmut, 1933-1950, 1979, undated (Box 12, Folder 198)
  - Diamond, Jared, 1985, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 199)
  - Dictionary of Scientific Biography, 1969, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 200)
  - Dingman, Jane, 1974-1981 (Box 12, Folder 201)
  - Dingwall, Eugene Davidson, 1944-1955 (Box 12, Folder 202)
  - Dobzhansky, Th., 1946-1947, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 203)
  - Dodd family, 1971, 1979-1988 (Box 12, Folder 204)
  - Dodson, Stanley, 1966, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 205)
  - Dreyer, William (Box 13, Folder 225)
  - Drouet, Francis, 1941-1945 (Box 12, Folder 206)
  - Dubos, René, 1951, 1964, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 207)
  - Duke University, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 208)
  - Dunbar, Max, 1941, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 209)
  - Dunn, Curtis, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 210)
  - Dunn, L. C. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    See also: Series I, folder 27
  - Durden, Christopher J., 1971-1973 (Box 12, Folder 211)
  - Durrell, Gerald, 1974-1986 (Box 12, Folder 212)
  - Dymond, J. R., 1948-1951 (Box 12, Folder 213)
  - Ea-Er, 1921-1991, undated (Box 12, Folder 214 - 221)
  - Es-Ew, 1930-1989 (Box 13, Folder 222)
  - Eccles, David H., 1954-1969 (Box 13, Folder 223)
  - Ecological Monographs, 1938-1950, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 224)
  - Ecological Society of America, 1937-1950, 1970-1990 (Box 13, Folder 225)
  - Ecologists Union, 1948-1950 (Box 13, Folder 226)
  - Ecology, 1940-1947 (Box 13, Folder 227 - 228)
  - Edmondson, W. Thomas and Yvette
    See also: Series III, folder 329-331
    - 1937-1959 (Box 13, Folder 229 - 236)
    - 1960-1991 (Box 14, Folder 237 - 246)
  - Ehrlich, Paul R., 1974-1990 (Box 15, Folder 247 - 248)
  - Eisner, Thomas, 1971-1972, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 249)
  - Elizabethan Club, 1947-1990, undated (Box 15, Folder 250 - 253)
  - Ellis, Gordon H., 1944-1946 (Box 15, Folder 254)
  - Ellsworth, Phoebe, 1974-1990 (Box 15, Folder 255 - 258)
    See also: Series I, folder 507
  - Elton, Charles, 1943-1952, 1976-1977 (Box 15, Folder 259)
  - Emmanuel College (University of Cambridge), 1981-1989 (Box 15, Folder 260)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1944-1970 (Box 16, Folder 261)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica Roof Conference, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 262 - 265)
  - Epiphany Philosophers, 1960-1964 (Box 16, Folder 266)
  - Eugster, Hans P., 1973-1975 (Box 16, Folder 267)
  - Evans, Francis, 1947-1948, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 268)
  - Ewing, Maurice, 1950-1954 (Box 16, Folder 269)
  - Fa-Fo, 1928-1988 (Box 16, Folder 270 - 273)
  - Fr-Fu, F unidentified, 1937-1990 (Box 17, Folder 274 - 277)
  - Finerty, J. Patrick, 1970-1989 (Box 17, Folder 278 - 279)
  - Flannery, Dennis M. (Box 8, Folder 139-140)
    See also: Series I, folder 139-140
  - Fleischer, Michael (Box 19, Folder 310-311)
    See also: Series I, folder 310-311
  - Flint, Richard F., 1945 (Box 17, Folder 280)
    See also: Series II, folders 51-52
  - Florida State Museum, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 281)
  - Foley, Joseph, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 282)
  - Formozov, Nicholai A., 1975, 1981-1988 (Box 17, Folder 283)
  - Foster, H. Lincoln (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Fox, H. Munro, 1947-1951 (Box 17, Folder 284)
  - Franklin Institute, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 285)
  - Frey, David G., 1950-1983 (Box 17, Folder 286)
  - Friday, Laurie, 1988-1990 (Box 17, Folder 287)
  - Friedhoff, Richard M., 1983 (Box 17, Folder 288)
  - Fryer, G., 1952-1959, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 289)
  - Furth, David G., 1975-1983 (Box 17, Folder 290)
  - G, G unidentified, 1921-1990, undated (Box 18, Folder 291 - 303)
  - Garber, Marjorie B., 1975-1981, undated (Box 18, Folder 304 - 305)
  - Gaudreau, Denise, 1981, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 306)
  - Gauze, Georgii Franksevich, 1945-1987 (Box 18, Folder 307)
  - Geochemical Prospecting Section, 1950-1951 (Box 18, Folder 308)
  - Geological Society of America, 1947-1956 (Box 18, Folder 309)
  - Geological Survey (U.S.), 1944- 1984 (Box 19, Folder 310 - 311)
  - Gerould, John H., 1943 (Box 19, Folder 312)
  - Gianno, Rosemary, 1985-1989 (Box 19, Folder 313)
  - Gilbert, John J., 1967- 1983 (Box 19, Folder 314)
  - Glaus, Karen, 1969-1971 (Box 19, Folder 315)
    See also: Series I, folders 671-672
  - Goddard, David, 1949-1958 (Box 19, Folder 316)
  - Goertz, Mel, 1961-1982 (Box 19, Folder 317)
  - Goldhor, Susan, 1973-1990 (Box 19, Folder 318)
  - Goldman, Charles R., 1970-1984 (Box 19, Folder 319)
  - Goldsmith, T. H., 1978 (Box 19, Folder 320)
  - Golubic, John J., 1969-1973 (Box 19, Folder 321)
  - Gordon, Isabella, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 322)
  - Goreau, Thomas F., 1951-1968, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 323)
  - Gorham, Eville, 1953- 1960, 1980-1990 (Box 19, Folder 324)
  - Goulden, Clyde, 1962-1987 (Box 19, Folder 325 - 326)
  - Grant, Peter, 1970-1987 (Box 20, Folder 327)
  - Griffin, Don, 1938-1949, 1970-1972 (Box 20, Folder 328)
  - Grinevald, Jacques, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 329)
  - Griswold, A. Whitney, 1948- 1962 (Box 20, Folder 330)
  - Gritten, Mary, 1973-1978 (Box 20, Folder 331 - 333)
  - Guillard, Robert, 1953-1983 (Box 20, Folder 334)
  - Ha-Heg, 1921- 1989 (Box 20, Folder 335 - 339)
  - Hei-Hv, 1920-1990 (Box 21, Folder 340 - 343)
  - Hahn, Emily, 1970, 1983-1985 (Box 21, Folder 344)
  - Hairston, Nelson G., Jr., 1978-1988 (Box 21, Folder 345)
  - Hall, Diana Long, 1974-1977 (Box 21, Folder 346)
  - Haraway, Donna, 1969-1988 (Box 21, Folder 347)
  - Harcombe, Paul, 1969-1979 (Box 21, Folder 348)
  - Hardy, Alister C., 1950-1957, 1969, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 349)
  - Harper, John Lander, 1970-1984 (Box 21, Folder 350)
  - Harrower, Molly, 1976-1985 (Box 21, Folder 351)
  - Hart, C. W. (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
    See also: Series I, folder 12-14
  - Hartman, Willard D., 1943-1953, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 352)
  - Harvard University, 1968-1971 (Box 22, Folder 353)
  - Haskell, Edward F., 1947-1983 (Box 22, Folder 354)
  - Hasler, Arthur D., 1941-1990 (Box 22, Folder 355)
  - Havas, Magda, 1982-1983 (Box 22, Folder 356)
  - Hawkes, H. E., 1946-1958 (Box 22, Folder 357)
  - Heathcote, Isobel, 1976-1980 (Box 22, Folder 358)
  - Heller, Amy, 1983-1984 (Box 22, Folder 359)
  - Heller, John H., 1980-1983 (Box 22, Folder 360)
  - Hendricks, Sterling, 1944-1951 (Box 22, Folder 361)
  - Henson, Walt R., 1969-1984 (Box 22, Folder 362)
  - Horie, Shoji, 1972-1990 (Box 22, Folder 363)
  - Hsiao, Sidney, 1941-1949 (Box 22, Folder 364)
  - Hughes, Gwendolyn Ethel Rendle [Sah Oved], 1923-1982, undated (Box 22, Folder 365)
  - Hungerford, H. B., 1922-1958 (Box 22, Folder 366)
  - Huntington, Ellsworth, 1941-1945 (Box 22, Folder 367)
  - Huntington, Gertrude (Trudy) Enders, 1951-1957 (Box 22, Folder 368)
  - Hurlbert, Stuart H., 1977-1984 (Box 22, Folder 369)
  - Hutchins, Louis W., 1941-1955 (Box 23, Folder 370)
  - Hutchinson, A. Leslie, 1937-1985 (Box 23, Folder 371)
  - Hutchinson, Arthur and Evaline Demezy, 1904, 1926-1954, undated (Box 23, Folder 372 - 374)
  - Hutchinson, Dorothea, 1961-1990, undated (Box 23, Folder 375 - 380)
  - Hutchinson, Hannah, 1981-1989 (Box 23, Folder 381)
  - Hutchinson, Margaret, 1931-1965, undated (Box 23, Folder 382 - 383)
  - Hutchinson family, 1973-1991, undated (Box 23, Folder 384)
  - Huxley, Julian, 1945-1962 (Box 23, Folder 385)
  - Hyde, Fred, 1977-1986 (Box 23, Folder 386)
  - I, 1930-1988 (Box 23, Folder 387 - 388)
  - Inamori Foundation, 1986-1990 (Box 24, Folder 389)
  - Institute for Intercultural Studies, 1970-1982 (Box 24, Folder 390)
    See also: Series I, folder 535
  - International Association of Theoretical and Applied Limnology, 1939-1991, undated (Box 24, Folder 391 - 394)
  - Isay, Jane, 1973-1986 (Box 24, Folder 395)
  - ISIS, 1972-1978 (Box 24, Folder 396)
  - Isle of Wight Natural History and Archaeological Society, 1970-1986 (Box 24, Folder 397)
  - Ja-Ji, 1937-1988 (Box 24, Folder 398)
  - Jo-Ju, 1947-1986 (Box 25, Folder 399 - 400)
  - Jackson, Jeremy, 1960-1981 (Box 25, Folder 401)
  - Jackson, Togwell A., 1967-1973 (Box 25, Folder 402)
  - Jahn, Theodore L., 1950-1957 (Box 25, Folder 403)
  - Jenkin, Penelope ("Clops"), 1937-1987 (Box 25, Folder 404)
  - John and Alice Tyler Ecology-Energy Fund, 1974-1989 (Box 25, Folder 405)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1948-1962 (Box 25, Folder 406)
  - John Wiley and Sons, Inc., 1945-1990 (Box 25, Folder 407 - 413)
  - Jolly, Alison Bishop, 1961-1987 (Box 26, Folder 414)
  - Jones, Charles F. And Susannah, 1950-1967 (Box 26, Folder 415)
  - Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation, 1946-1958 (Box 26, Folder 416)
  - Juday, Chancey, 1931-1941 (Box 26, Folder 417)
  - K, 1937-1990 (Box 26, Folder 418 - 423)
  - Kamen, Martin D., 1945-1983 (Box 26, Folder 424)
  - Kassarjian, Mary Catherine Bateson (Box 5, Folder 78)
    See also: Series I, folder 78
  - Keating, Kathleen, 1974-1989 (Box 26, Folder 425 - 428)
  - Keller, J. D., 1946 (Box 26, Folder 429)
  - Kerfoot, W. Charles, 1977-1986 (Box 26, Folder 430)
  - Kerr, Paul F., 1945-1948 (Box 26, Folder 431)
  - King, Charles E., 1967-1975 (Box 26, Folder 432)
  - King, Robert Charles, 1956-1978 (Box 26, Folder 433)
  - Kingsland, Sharon, 1978-1987, undated (Box 27, Folder 434 - 436)
  - Kinzie, Robert, 1968-1983 (Box 27, Folder 437)
  - Klopfer, Peter, 1956-1978 (Box 27, Folder 438)
  - Koestler, Arthur, 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 439)
  - Kohn, Alan J., 1955-1989 (Box 27, Folder 440)
  - Kolasa, Jerzy, 1983-1984 (Box 27, Folder 441)
  - Kubie, Lawrence S., 1952-1959 (Box 27, Folder 442)
  - Kubler, George, 1946-1983, undated (Box 27, Folder 443)
  - Kuhn, Thomas S., 1970 (Box 27, Folder 444)
  - Kuiper, Gerard P., 1954 (Box 27, Folder 445)
  - La-Lo, 1925-1990 (Box 27, Folder 446 - 450)
  - Lu-Ly, 1941-1945 (Box 28, Folder 451)
  - Lack, David, 1947-1975 (Box 28, Folder 452)
  - Ladd, Henry S., 1945-1956 (Box 28, Folder 453)
  - Lane, Abbot, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 454)
  - Lane, Meredith, 1984-1985 (Box 28, Folder 455)
  - Lane, Patricia, 1969-1983 (Box 28, Folder 456)
  - Lang, Judy, 1966-1979 (Box 28, Folder 457)
  - Langenheim, Jean H., 1986 (Box 28, Folder 458)
  - Lansbury, Ivor, 1954-1989 (Box 28, Folder 459)
  - Larison, Lorraine, 1968-1985 (Box 28, Folder 460 - 461)
  - Lawson, John D., 1947-1948 (Box 28, Folder 462)
  - Lee, Sidney, 1949-1984 (Box 28, Folder 463)
  - Lehmann, John T., 1981-1987 (Box 28, Folder 464)
  - Leigh, Egbert, 1967-1986 (Box 28, Folder 465)
  - Leopold, Estella B., 1953-1982 (Box 28, Folder 466)
    - Oversize (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Leppard, Gary G., 1975 (Box 28, Folder 467)
  - Leventhal, Elaine, 1968-1969 (Box 28, Folder 468)
  - Levin, Simon A., 1983 (Box 28, Folder 469)
  - Lewin, Joyce and Ralph, 1952-1974 (Box 28, Folder 470)
  - Lewis, C. Bernard, 1945-1952 (Box 28, Folder 471)
  - Lewis, William M., Jr., 1977-1984 (Box 28, Folder 472)
  - Lewontin, Richard C., 1969-1974 (Box 28, Folder 473)
  - Libby, W. F., 1947-1974 (Box 28, Folder 474)
  - Library of Congress, 1941-1977 (Box 29, Folder 475)
  - Liebert, Herman [Fritz], 1972-1983 (Box 29, Folder 476)
  - Likens, Gene E., 1972-1986 (Box 29, Folder 477)
  - Lillich, Meredith, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 478)
  - Lillie, N. S. P. [Sylvia], 1974 (Box 29, Folder 479)
  - Limnological Society of America (Box 2, Folder 33-39)
    See also: Series I, folder 33-39
  - Limnology and Oceanography (Box 14, Folder 237-246)
    See also: Series I, folder 237-246
  - Lin, Qi-bin, 1985-1987 (Box 29, Folder 480)
  - Lindeman, Eleanor and Raymond, 1940-1941, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 481)
  - Linnean Society of London, 1946-1985 (Box 29, Folder 482)
  - Lipset, David A., 1979-1980 (Box 29, Folder 483)
  - Livingston, Daniel A., 1950-1990 (Box 29, Folder 484 - 486)
  - Löffler, Heinz, 1955-1961, 1981-1982 (Box 29, Folder 487)
  - Lohmann, Carl A. (Box 53, Folder 901)
    See also: Series I, folder 901
  - Lovejoy, Thomas E., Jr.
    - 1974-1979 (Box 29, Folder 488 - 491)
    - 1980-1990 (Box 30, Folder 492 - 493)
  - Lovering, T. S., 1948-1954 (Box 30, Folder 494)
  - Lundblad, O., 1928-1940 (Box 30, Folder 495 - 496)
  - Ma-Mo, 1937-1991 (Box 30, Folder 497 - 502)
  - Mu-My, M uidentified, 1940-1987 (Box 31, Folder 503 - 504)
  - Macan, T. T., 1940-1986 (Box 31, Folder 505)
    See also: Series I, folder 391-394
  - MacArthur, Elizabeth, 1954-1986 (Box 31, Folder 506)
  - MacArthur, Robert H., 1952-1972 (Box 31, Folder 507)
    - Restricted (Box 114, Folder 1)
      Conditions Governing Access
      In accordance with the deed of gift to this collection, this correspondence is restricted until 2035
  - MacClintock, Dorcas, 1972-1987 (Box 31, Folder 508)
  - MacLane, Saunders, 1973-1981 (Box 31, Folder 509)
  - MacLeod, Norman, 1983-1990 (Box 31, Folder 510)
  - MacMillan Company, 1936-1969 (Box 31, Folder 511)
  - Maland, Joanne, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 512)
  - Mangum, Charlotte, 1984-1989 (Box 31, Folder 513)
  - Mansbridge, F. Ronald (Box 31, Folder 511)
    See also: Series I, folder 511
  - Marcuse, Sibyl, 1971-1984 (Box 31, Folder 514)
  - Marglef, Ramón, 1963-1985 (Box 31, Folder 515)
  - Margulis, Lynn, 1967-1991 (Box 31, Folder 516 - 517)
  - Martin, Paul S., 1957-1968 (Box 31, Folder 518)
  - Martindale, Andrew, 1971-1981 (Box 31, Folder 519)
  - Mason, Brian, 1949-1950 (Box 31, Folder 520)
  - Mathewson, John, 1945-1949 (Box 31, Folder 521)
  - May, Robert, 1972-1988 (Box 31, Folder 522)
  - Mayr, Ernst, 1948-1987 (Box 31, Folder 523)
    See also: Series I, folder 564
  - McConnell, Duncan, 1944-1970 (Box 32, Folder 524)
  - McConnell, R. A., 1947-1980 (Box 32, Folder 525 - 527)
  - McCormick, Ada, 1952 (Box 32, Folder 528)
  - McCulloch, Warren S., 1946-1965 (Box 32, Folder 529)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., 1940-1978 (Box 32, Folder 530)
  - McKaye, Kenneth Robert, 1976-1982 (Box 32, Folder 531)
  - McLauren, Ian, 1958-1980 (Box 32, Folder 532)
  - McMahon, Brian, 1945-1948 (Box 32, Folder 533)
  - McNaughton, S. J., 1971-1983 (Box 32, Folder 534)
  - Mead, Margaret, 1944-1973 (Box 32, Folder 535)
    See also: Series I, folder 390
  - Menaker, Walter, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 536)
  - Merriman, Daniel, 1945-1983 (Box 32, Folder 537)
  - Meselson, Matthew, 1974-1990 (Box 32, Folder 538)
  - Michael, George, 1972-1978 (Box 32, Folder 539)
  - Michigan State University, 1950-1951 (Box 32, Folder 540)
  - Miller, Richard S., 1950-1982 (Box 32, Folder 541)
  - Mills, Eric L., 1974-1987 (Box 32, Folder 542)
  - Mininberg, Julien, 1985-1986 (Box 32, Folder 543)
  - Miskimin, Alice A., 1969-1981 (Box 32, Folder 544)
  - Moehlman, Patricia D., 1982-1986 (Box 32, Folder 545)
  - Moore, J. E., 1940-1946 (Box 33, Folder 546)
  - Moore, Jerrold, 1970-1984 (Box 33, Folder 547)
  - Mortimer, C. H., 1942-1984 (Box 33, Folder 548)
  - Mosley, Christina, 1979-1986 (Box 33, Folder 549)
  - Murphy, Robert Cushman, 1943-1949 (Box 33, Folder 550)
  - N, 1933-1989, undated (Box 33, Folder 551 - 555)
  - National Academy of Sciences
    See also: Series II, folder 1-3
    - General, 1950-1991 (Box 33, Folder 556 - 559)
    - Armed Forces - NRC Committee on Bio-Astronautics, 1959 (Box 33, Folder 560)
    - Charles Doolittle Walcott Fund Board of Trustees, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 561)
    - Committee on Science and Public Policy (COSPUP), 1965-1966 (Box 34, Folder 562)
    - Cottrell Award for Environmental Quality Committee, 1971-1974 (Box 34, Folder 563)
    - Daniel Giraud Elliot Fund Committee, 1951-1953, 1970-1971, 1984, undated (Box 34, Folder 564)
    - Environmental Studies Board, 1968-1972 (Box 34, Folder 565 - 569)
    - Marcellus Hartley Fund Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 34, Folder 570)
    - National Research Committee, 1946-1953 (Box 34, Folder 571)
    - Proceedings Office, 1953, 1970-1988 (Box 34, Folder 572)
    - Reports Review Committee
      - General, 1970-1980, undated (Box 34, Folder 573 - 574)
      - "Assessment of Biomedical Technologies", 1972-1975 (Box 35, Folder 575 - 577)
      - Committee on the Effects of Herbicides in Vietnam
        - 1971-1973 April (Box 35, Folder 578-581)
        - 1973 April-October (Box 36, Folder 582-589)
        - 1973 November-1974 January (Box 37, Folder 590-594)
        - 1974 February-Aug, undated (Box 38, Folder 595)
      - Committee to Evaluate the International Biological Program, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 596)
      - Jamaica Bay Environment Study, 1970-1971 (Box 38, Folder 597)
    - Section of Population Biology, Evolution and Ecology (27), 1976-1991 (Box 38, Folder 598 - 599)
    - Space Science Board, 1959, 1970, 1974 (Box 38, Folder 600)
    - Temporary Nominating Group for Environmental and Field Biology, 1972-1974 (Box 38, Folder 601 - 603)
    - Temporary Nominating Group in Behavioral Sciences, 1962-1963 (Box 38, Folder 604)
    - Temporary Nominating Group in Systematic and Environmental Biology, 1967-1969 (Box 38, Folder 605 - 606)
    - Temporary Nominating Group, unidentified
      - undated (Box 38, Folder 607)
      - undated (Box 39, Folder 608)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Inc. Science Committee (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - National Research Council, 1946-1980 (Box 39, Folder 609 - 610)
    See also: Series I, folder 768
  - National Science Foundation, 1952-1953, 1960-1989, undated (Box 39, Folder 611)
  - Nature, 1937-1970 (Box 39, Folder 612)
  - Needham, Joseph, 1945-1984 (Box 39, Folder 613)
  - Neess, John C., 1948-1963 (Box 39, Folder 614)
  - Nemoy, Leon, 1976-1980 (Box 39, Folder 615)
  - Neuman, Jehuda, 1954-1956 (Box 39, Folder 616)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1941-1973 (Box 39, Folder 617)
  - New York Review of Books, 1972-1990 (Box 39, Folder 618)
  - Newcombe, Curtis L., 1946-1953 (Box 39, Folder 619)
  - Newell, Irwin M., 1944-1973 (Box 39, Folder 620)
  - Nims, Leslie, 1947-1949 (Box 39, Folder 621)
    See also: Series I, folder 107
  - O, 1929-1985 (Box 39, Folder 622 - 625)
  - Odum, Eugene P., 1949-1986 (Box 39, Folder 626)
  - Odum, Howard T., 1948-1989 (Box 39, Folder 627)
  - Österreichische Akademie der Wissenschaften, 1984-1987 (Box 39, Folder 628)
  - Ohio State University, 1970-1971 (Box 39, Folder 629)
  - Ohle, Waldemar, 1950-1980 (Box 39, Folder 630)
  - Ohlhorst, Sharon, 1974-1984 (Box 40, Folder 631)
  - Oliver, Charles, 1971-1976 (Box 40, Folder 632)
  - Omer-Cooper, Joseph, 1929-1949 (Box 40, Folder 633)
  - Oppenheimer, Jane, 1941-1978 (Box 40, Folder 634)
  - Ordway, Jane, 1949-1971 (Box 40, Folder 635)
  - Orion Nature Quarterly, 1982-1983 (Box 40, Folder 636)
  - Oved, Sah (Box 22, Folder 365)
    See also: Series I, folder 365
  - Oved, Yemaiel, 1940-1966 (Box 40, Folder 637)
    See also: Series I, folder 56
  - P, 1920-1989 (Box 40, Folder 638 - 643)
  - Pan American Union, 1946 (Box 40, Folder 644)
  - Pantin, Carl F. A., 1950-1966 (Box 40, Folder 645)
  - Park, Thomas, 1949-1960 (Box 40, Folder 646)
    See also: Series I, folders 227-228
  - Parker, Pamela J., 1978-1979 (Box 40, Folder 647)
  - Parr, Albert E., 1941-1956 (Box 41, Folder 648)
    See also: Series I, folder 834; Series II, folder 52
  - Passano, L. M., 1951-1964 (Box 41, Folder 649)
  - Paterson, Hugh E., 1976-1980 (Box 41, Folder 650)
  - Patrick, Ruth, 1938-1991 (Box 41, Folder 651 - 653)
  - Patten, Bernard C., Jr., 1957-1964 (Box 41, Folder 654)
  - Paynter, Raymond A., Jr., 1948-1969 (Box 41, Folder 655)
  - Peabody Museum of Natural History, 1976-1987 (Box 41, Folder 656)
  - Peacey, Patrick, 1974-1986 (Box 41, Folder 657)
  - Pearce, E. Justin, 1962-1977 (Box 41, Folder 658)
  - Pearse, A. S. (Box 13, Folder 224)
    See also: Series I, folder 224
  - Peckarsky, Barbara, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 659)
  - Pell, Herbert, 1941-1967 (Box 41, Folder 660)
  - Pennak, Robert W., 1935-1984 (Box 41, Folder 661)
  - Peters, Walter, 1949-1980 (Box 41, Folder 662)
  - Pettijohn, F. J., 1950-1951 (Box 41, Folder 663)
  - Pickford, Grace E.
    - 1932-1947 (Box 41, Folder 664 - 666)
    - 1971-1986 (Box 42, Folder 667)
  - Pierce, Naomi, 1977-1990 (Box 42, Folder 668)
  - Poisson, Raymond, 1929-1980 (Box 42, Folder 669)
  - Porter, H. Boone, 1966-1981 (Box 42, Folder 670)
  - Porter, James W. And Karen G., 1969-1990, undated (Box 42, Folder 671 - 672)
  - Posner, Gerald S., 1949-1971 (Box 42, Folder 673)
  - Poulson, Donald, 1947-1990 (Box 42, Folder 674)
  - Powell, Jeffrey R., 1977-1982 (Box 42, Folder 675)
  - Prashad, Baini, 1933-1939 (Box 42, Folder 676)
  - Prescott, G. W., 1937-1966 (Box 42, Folder 677)
  - Press, Michelle, 1979-1983 (Box 42, Folder 678)
  - Preston, Frank W., 1953-1983 (Box 42, Folder 679)
  - Princeton University Press, 1951-1982 (Box 42, Folder 680)
  - Proctor, Vernon, 1956-1975 (Box 42, Folder 681)
  - Provalosi, Luigi, 1953-1987 (Box 42, Folder 682)
  - Q, 1952-1987 (Box 42, Folder 683)
  - Quarterly Review of Biology, 1942-1979 (Box 42, Folder 684)
  - Ra-Ro, 1923-1991 (Box 42, Folder 685 - 688)
  - Ru-Ry, 1936-1982 (Box 43, Folder 689)
  - Racek, A. A., 1962-1984 (Box 43, Folder 690)
  - Rachoutin, Stan, 1977-1985 (Box 43, Folder 691)
  - Radiation Counter Laboratories, 1946-1955 (Box 43, Folder 692)
  - Randall, Lilian M. C., 1969-1974 (Box 43, Folder 693)
  - Rankama, Kalervo, 1946-1956 (Box 43, Folder 694)
  - Rawson, D. S., 1935-1957 (Box 43, Folder 695)
  - Ray, Gordon N., 1970-1980 (Box 43, Folder 696)
    See also: Series I, folder 406
  - Redfield, Alfred C., 1944-1957 (Box 43, Folder 697)
  - Reed, Charles A., 1964-1977 (Box 43, Folder 698)
  - Reiswig, Henry M., 1971-1972 (Box 43, Folder 699)
  - Remington, Charles L., 1948-1990 (Box 43, Folder 700)
  - Rendle, Gwendolyn Ethel (Box 22, Folder 365)
  - Renn, Charles E., 1948-1958 (Box 43, Folder 701)
  - Revelle, Roger, 1951-1957 (Box 43, Folder 702)
  - Reynoldson, T. B., 1970-1987 (Box 43, Folder 703)
  - Rhine, J. B., 1948-1971 (Box 43, Folder 704)
  - Rich, Peter, 1972-1985 (Box 43, Folder 705)
  - Ricker, W. E., 1944-1946 (Box 43, Folder 706)
  - Riessen, Howard, 1979-1990 (Box 43, Folder 707)
  - Riley, Gordon, 1937-1985 (Box 43, Folder 708)
  - Ripley, S. Dillon
    - 1946-1973 (Box 43, Folder 709 - 710)
    - 1974-1991, undated (Box 44, Folder 711 - 715)
  - Ritterbush, Philip C., 1962-1985, undated (Box 44, Folder 716 - 718)
  - Ritvo, Lucille B., 1965-1990 (Box 44, Folder 719)
  - Robbins, Eleanora I., 1980-1985 (Box 44, Folder 720 - 721)
    See also: Sereis III, folder 177
  - Roberts, H. Radclyffe (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
  - Robinson, W. O., 1941-1958 (Box 44, Folder 722)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1947-1963 (Box 44, Folder 723)
  - Rodhe, Wilhelm, 1941-1974 (Box 45, Folder 724)
  - Rosenberg, Miriam, 1969-1973 (Box 45, Folder 725)
  - Rosenzweig, Michael, 1965-1979 (Box 45, Folder 726)
  - Rossiter, Margaret, 1974-1984 (Box 45, Folder 727)
  - Roth, Virginia Louise, 1978-1984 (Box 45, Folder 728 - 729)
  - Rothschild, Miriam, 1959-1984 (Box 45, Folder 730)
  - Royal Society, 1983-1990 (Box 45, Folder 731)
    See also: Series II, folders 1-3
  - Rubey, William W., 1948-1959 (Box 45, Folder 732)
  - Ruddle, Frank H., 1977-1990 (Box 45, Folder 733)
  - Rudnick, Dorothea, 1952-1982 (Box 45, Folder 734)
  - Ruff, Willie, 1976-1986 (Box 45, Folder 735)
  - Rushton, William A. H., 1938-1980 (Box 45, Folder 736)
  - Ruttner, Franz, 1947-1959 (Box 45, Folder 737)
  - Sa-Se, 1933-1986 (Box 45, Folder 738 - 740)
  - Sh-Sz, 1935-1989 (Box 46, Folder 741 - 751)
  - Sagan, Carl, 1973-1983 (Box 46, Folder 752)
  - Sanders, Howard Lawrence, 1951-1988 (Box 46, Folder 753)
  - Sapir, Edward, 1936 (Box 46, Folder 754)
  - Sargent, C. Forbes, 1939-1942 (Box 46, Folder 755)
  - Saxl, Lea, 1962-1963 (Box 46, Folder 756)
  - Saybrook College (Yale University), 1941-1991 (Box 46, Folder 757)
  - Scannell, Maura, 1981-1988 (Box 46, Folder 758)
  - Schmitt, Waldo L., 1946-1947 (Box 46, Folder 759)
  - Schurman, Johanna F. M., 1928-1933 (Box 46, Folder 760)
  - Schwarz, Ernst, 1947-1957 (Box 46, Folder 761)
  - Science, 1946-1983 (Box 47, Folder 762)